Guide to the Lucille Borella collection, 1967-2000 MS 692
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Lucille Borella collection
1967-2000
1967-1977
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Borella, Lucille
MS 692
0.75 Linear Feet (1 box)
3.78 Gigabytes (Nearline access: MS0692aip_001 (3.78 GB)
1.05 Gigabytes (Nearline access: MS0692aip_002 (1.05 GB)
1.13 Gigabytes (Nearline access: MS0692aip_003 (1.13 GB)
This collection consists of news clippings, photographs, and 2-track audio reels.
Biographical / Historical
In the late 1960s, Bill and Lucille Cade formed a folk duo. Over the next several years, they performed throughout the region. They played in Houston venues, such as Anderson Fair Retail Restaurant, the UH Coffee House, and the Wooden Nickel Club, as well the college ciruit in and out of the state. They also performed at Kerrville Folk Festival in 1974 with their young baby in tow.
Around 1976, Bill and Lucille Cade broke up. Later on, Lucille, now Borella, began performing with her husband Larry at Anderson Fair in 1979 under the name Larry & Lucille.
While no longer actively performing, Lucille Borella has stayed a member of the folk community. She and her husband support the Dripping Springs Songwriters Festival.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains news clippings, contracts, photographs, and 2-track audio reels from Lucille Borella's folk duo Bill and Lucille Cade. It also contains 2-track audio reels of her music collaboration with her husband Larry Borella.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Lucille Borella in March 2017.
Related Materials
Please see the Rice University KTRU Radio records, UA 011.
Index Terms
Subjects
Music; Folk music -- Texas -- Houston; Women
Document Types
Folk music
- Series I: General
  - Alley Gala, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Contracts, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - News clippings, 1968-2000 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photographs and proofs, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series II: Audio
  - Home recordings (2-track reel), ca. 1967 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp4. Contents include: Track 1: Bill and Lucille Cade playing at home with others; Track 2: Bill and Lucille Cade playing at home with others, including Steve Stevens
  - Bill and Lucille Cade (2-track reel), 1960s (Box 1)
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp4. Contents include: Track 1: Live performance; Track 2: Lucille Cade solo
  - Durant Folk Festival (2-track reel), 1971-02-06 (Box 1)
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp4. Contents include: Bill and Lucille Cade at the Durant Folk Festival
  - Birth announcement (2-track reel), 1972 (Box 1)
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp4. Contents include: Announcement of Coleen Cade's birth on KPFT by Captain Macho aka Dan Earhart.
  - Studio recordings (2-track reel), 1973-03-01 (Box 1)
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp4. Contents include: Studio recordings at Dale Mullins Studios, 4 tracks
  - Friends show (2-track reel), 1975 (Box 1)
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp4. Contents include: Track 1: Bill and Lucille Cade live performance on Friends show; Track 2: Bill Cade studio recordings
  - Practice tape (2-track reel), 1970s (Box 1)
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp4. Contents include: Track 1 and 2: Practice recordings of Bill and Lucille Cade at home
  - Bill and Lucille Cade (2-track reel) (Box 1)
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp4. Contents include: Live performances and demos
  - Picking Party (2-track reel), ca. 1976 (Box 1)
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp4. Contents include: Track 1: Picking party including performance by Reb Smith, George Ensle, Stephen Jarrard, France Files Jarrard, Lucille Borella, and Larry Borella; Track 2: Lucille and Larry Borella recording at home
  - Picker Poets Reunion, 1985-04-06
    Contents include: Live concert recorded by KPFT. Performers include: Jerry Jeff Walker, Guy Clark, K.T. Oslin, Townes Van Zandt, Rodney Crowell, Mickey Newbury.
  - Reb Smith, 1975-1982
    Contents include: master wav files and access jpg files. Tracks include: "These Days" at Tandy's, "Bag Pipe Concerto," "Darcy Farrow," "Melodramma," "Storm at Sea," "Tonda," and a performance at the University of Houston.